Bradley family papers
Connecticut Historical Society
Bradley family Papers
1703-1868
Connecticut Historical Society, Hartford, Connecticut
Bradley family
0.25 linear feet (1/2 box)
Biographical Sketch
William Bradley was an early settler of New Haven. He and his wife Alice Prichard Bradley had several sons, among them Joseph (1645-1705) and Abraham (1650-1718). Abraham’s family line is the one most represented in this collection.
Abraham and his wife Hannah Thompson Bradley had son Daniel (1679-1723) who married Sarah Bassett. She married Isaac Johnson after Daniel’s death. Daniel and Sarah had sons Stephen (1702-1740), Daniel (1706-1773), Amos (1746-1819) and Moses (1721-1804). Stephen’s sons were Stephen (1726-1800), Elisha (1732-1815) and Josiah (1735-1760).
Daniel Bradley (1706-1773) married Abigail Punchard in 1726. They had sons Daniel (1727-1821), William (1730-1809), Jabez (1733-1793), Jesse (1736-1812) and Joel (1738-1801). Daniel’s brother Amos (1746-1819) married Olive Doolittle (1761-1813) in 1777 and they had, among their other children, a daughter named Olive (1786-1857). Daniel’s son Joel lived in Hamden, married Abigail Tuttle (1740-1828) in 1760 and they had a son Amasa (1762-1827) who had sons Horace (1787-1870) and Sterling (1793-1868) with his wife Martha Bradley.
Abraham Bradley’s brother Joseph (1645-1705) had a great grandson named Alvin (1734-1810) who married Martha Gilbert.
A detailed genealogy of the Bradley family may be found in Families of Ancient New Haven. Donald Lines Jacobus, compiler. Vol. 1. (Baltimore, 1981)
Scope and Content
To the extent possible, the papers in this collection are organized by family group. For example, Abraham had son Daniel, who had sons Stephen and Daniel, so Abraham’s papers are first, followed by those of his sons.
The bulk of the documents in this collection are deeds for land in New Haven or Hamden, and estate inventories and distribution. Where both exist for an individual, the deeds are arranged first, then the estate papers. Abraham, Daniel (1679-1723), Daniel (1706-1773) Joel and Amasa all have deeds in their papers. Estate records exist for Daniel (1679-1723), Stephen, Daniel (1706-1773), Joel, his wife Abigail, Amasa, Sterling and Olive. Hand written family records can be found in the papers of Daniel (1706-1773), Joel and Horace. The estate records of Olive could be those for the daughter and the mother, or for just one of them. Sterling is unique in that his papers include a series of short poems written in 1805.
Alvin is the only individual not in the Abraham-Daniel-Daniel line. His father was the grandson of Joseph. His papers consist of an estate inventory and distribution, 1809, and an inventory of his wife’s estate, undated.
The final folder of the collection contains an estate inventory for Sarah Bradley, 1749/50, an estate inventory of Aaron Bradley, 1809, a bill to “Mr. Bradley”, 1829, and a deed to Marietta Bradley in 1868.
Two unidentified documents were removed at the time of purchase and added to the French and Indian Wars Papers collection.
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the collection.
Accruals
The collection is closed.
Subject Headings
Personal Names
Bradley, Abraham, 1650-1718.; Bradley, Amasa, 1762-1827.; Bradley, Daniel, 1679-1723.; Bradley, Daniel, 1706-1773.; Bradley, Joel, 1738-1801?; Bradley, Stephen, 1702-1740.; Bradley, Sterling, 1793-1868.
Contents:
- I. Papers
  - Abraham Bradley deeds, 1703, 1709 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daniel Bradley (1679-1723) deeds, 1711, 1719 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Daniel (1679-1723) will, 1723, inventory, 1723/4 and distribution, 1728, of his estate, deed of wife Sarah, 1725 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Stephen Bradley estate inventory, 1740, accounts for settling estate, 1740-1741, probate court document, 1747 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Daniel Bradley (1706-1773) deeds, legal and financial records, 1742-1768, and family record, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Daniel Bradley (1706-1773) will, 1767, estate inventories, 1773 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Joel Bradley deeds, 1767-1770, promissory note, 1775 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Joel Bradley family record, undated, will and estate distribution, 1801 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Abigail Tuttle Bradley estate inventory and distribution, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Amasa Bradley deeds, 1791, 1802, court record, 1802 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Amasa Bradley estate inventory and accounts, 1827-1828 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Horace Bradley family record, ca. 1814, deed, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sterling Bradley poems, 1805, will, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Olive Bradley will, 1857, estate inventory and sale of effects at auction, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Alvin Bradley estate inventory and distribution, 1809, inventory of Widow Martha's estate, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)